

## Ocktaria Irmayanti Putri

ocktaria\_irmayanti@windowslive.com

## **INTRODUCTION**

Having experience as a Consultant which develop few client, maintaining Client about what kind of candidates that they are looking for, screening candidate's CV, making interview schedule with candidates and sent them to suitable user. Also as a trainer, i'm giving subject about how to deal with interview session especially for fresh graduated. The most significant project is to responsible in retaining of staff attrition, which has resulted to lower turnover than before.

In the latest 3,5 years leading Human Resources Departement at well known E-commerce company, develop, maintain organizations and work structure, planning, monitoring and ensure legal compliance for whole company.

#### **CONTACT DETAIL**

Place/DOB : Bandar Lampung / October 30

Address : Bukit Raya Cinere Street No.72, Cinere, Depok, 16512

Contact : +62811 8209391

Interests : Travelling, Fashion, Creative Ideas, Photograph, Musics

## **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

Formal Education :

Class 2006 : Senior High School 34, South Jakarta

Class 2009 : Diploma in Administration Monetary and Banking

University of Indonesia, Faculty of Social and Politics Science

2010 – 2012 : Bachelor in Marketing Management

**Indonesian Banking School** 

#### COURSES

1996- 2000 : Victoria English Course, Bandar Lampung

2002- 2006 : ILP English Course, Cinere

2004 : Guitar Classic Courses, Purwacaraka Music Studio

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

Enthusiastic, Responsible, Hardworker, Creative, Trustworthy

- Exceptional leaderhip, organizational, oral/written communication, interpersonal and problem resolution skills. Thrive in both independent and collaborative work environments.
- Enjoy dealing with people, active and friendly personalities
- Familiar with PC such as Microsoft Word, Excel, Power Point and Internet
- ➤ Hiring, Human Resources Management, Compensation Benefit and Wages structure, Performance Management, Employment Law, Organizations.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- > Certification of Saman Dance
- TOEFL LBI University of Indonesia (score 558)
- > Certification of Bancassurance
- > Certification of Computer Application for Business, University of Indonesia

### **ASSOCIATION**

- Fund and Event Committee of HSK 34, 2005
- Committee of Promnite 34, 2005
- Fund Leader Committee of 34 Cup 2005
- > Event Leader Committee of MK Fusion, 2006
- Deputy Leader Committee of Yearbook 34, 2006
- Miss Actuary And Banking 2006 2009
- Secretary of MABASA 2006
- Committee SHARE (Show That We Care) 2006
- Fund Leader Committee Olimpics of FISIP UI 2007
- Member of BEM FISIP UI 2008

- ➤ Leader Departemen of Public Relations, HMPS Banking 2008
- Fund Leader Committee A Tribute To Forest 2008
- ➤ Public Relations Leader Committee of Ramadhan with Orphans 2008
- ➤ Project Officer Sahur On The Road 2008
- ➤ Public Relations Leader Committee of Banking's Explorer 2008

# **WORKING EXPERIENCES**

Period	Company	Position
July - August 2008	Commonwealthlife, Sentra Mulia Tower 11 <sup>th</sup> floor	Internship
January – February 2009	PT. Bank Mandiri, Persero. Tbk , Plasa Bapindo 4 <sup>th</sup> Floor	Internship
February 2009 – February 2012	BSS Executive Search and Contract Personnel, Ampera	HR Consultant As Executive Trainer: (February 2009 – Sept 2009)  - Maintain relation to reputable university - Preparing schedule for training and syllable - Give training for fresh graduate about how to get success within interview session - Develop curriculum and training materials for fresh graduated - Deliver training program  As Recruitment Consultant: (Sept 2009 – Jan 2011) - Planning and develop sourcing of database to make sure that CV meets requirement that client looking for - Screening and scheduling candidates for interview

		session with client  - Placement candidates to the nearest location and also doing other recruitment processes.  - Checking and counting for pauli and SHL psikotes result  As Loyalty and Retention  Consultant:  (Jan 2011 – Feb 2012)  - Maintaining and retaining client to have another recruitment projects  - Responsible to recruiting and selection process in order to fulfill the manpower needs of different department  - Also responsible to retaining staff attrition to avoid high turnover  - Improved retain strategy to support high qualified employee  - Preparing loyalty event, and motivational program for best achievement and performances employee
February 2012 – Present	Rocket Internet GmbH, Germany http://www.rocket-internet.de/ PT. Fashion Eservices Indonesia	Human Capital Specialist (Assistant to HR Director)  Develop and Execute Recruiting plans.  - Network through industry contacts, association memberships, trade groups and employees.  - Plan for HR strategies in company  - Controlling manpower

- planning for all divisions in company
- Manage HR Selection and Recruitment Selection process with good quality of work
- Coordinate and implement college recruiting initiatives.
- Work with hiring managers on recruiting planning meetings.
- Create job descriptions.
- Lead the creation of a recruiting and interviewing plan for each open position.
- Efficiently and effectively fill open positions.
- Conduct regular followup with managers to determine the effectiveness of recruiting plans and implementation.
- Develop a pool of qualified candidates in advance of need.
- Research and recommend new sources for active and passive candidate recruiting.
- Build networks to find qualified passive candidates.
- Create company's regulations based on manpower regulation which valid in Indonesia
- Create an attractive Compensation and Benefit based on organizational structure.
- Developing Human
   Capital and the
   organizations for each
   division

- Maintaining database by post openings in newspaper advertisements, with professional organizations, and in other position appropriate venues.

# Administrative Duties and Record Keeping

- Manage the use of recruiters, headhunter and also payroll outsourcing.
- Review applicants to evaluate if they meet the position requirements.
- Conduct prescreening interviews.
- Assist in performing reference and background checks for potential employees.
- Assist in writing and forwarding rejection letters.
- Assist in interviewing and selecting employees onsite.
- Assist in preparing and sending offer packages.
- Maintaining personnel administrative agreement and work, such as passed probation, performance appraisal, administrative control of personnel, warning letter, termination letter, etc.
- Delivery end-to end resignation process to ensure exit process is done properly
- Preparing report exit to be submitted to management
- In coordination with

		Compensation Benefit for
		delivery involves salary
		proposal for new hiring,
		salary adjustment
		proposal for promoted
		employee, etc
		- Prepare Warning Letter
		for employees
		- Supports Business HR
		Manager in the review
		and implementation of
		local HR policies and also
		Regional HR systems,
		practices and processes to
		build workforce
		capability
		- Perform other special
		projects as assigned.
December 2013 -	Report directly to Local	<b>Head of Human Resources</b>
present	Director and Regional HR	Zalora Indonesia
	Director	
		Duties and Responsibilities:
		- To lead and support the
		development and
		implementation of HR
		policy across all areas of
		the organization including
		improving performance,
		maximising attendance and providing effective
		management of change.
		- Work with the HR team
		to develop, co-ordinate,
		implement and audit all
		HR activity within the
		department and across the
		organization.
		- Provide advice to
		managers on pay,
İ		
		conditions of service
		conditions of service matters, employee relations issues and

- policies taking into account current employment and case law to influence best practice and operational activity.
- Make proper arrangements for the effective recruitment of personnel to maintain the capacity and capability of the organisation.
- Maintain effective employee relations including participation, consultation and negotiation with representative bodies and ensure maintenance of productive working relationships with all colleagues.
- Ensure effective implementation of the disciplinary and grievance procedures for all division.
- Prepare employees for assignments by establishing and conducting company orientations and training program
- Maintain employee benefit programs and inform employees of benefit by studying and assessing benefit needs and trends; then recommending benefit program to management level
- Maintain management guidelines by preparing,

updating and recommending HR company policies and procedures
- Ensure legal compliance by monitoring and implementing applicable Human Resource federal and state requirements; conduct investigations; maintaining records and representing the organizations

# **AVAILABILITY TIME:**

➤ At least one month notice

I hereby declare that this Curriculum Vitae prepared in valid data by my good intention to be used by any parties needed.